<resources>
    <string name="app_name">HealthStride</string>
    <string name="what_is_blood_pressure">What is Blood Pressure?</string>
    <string name="answer_to_blood_pressure">Blood pressure is a measurement used in medicine. In the body, the arteries carry blood away from the heart. As blood travels through the arteries, it presses against the walls of the arteries. Blood pressure measures how hard the blood is pushing against the walls of the arteries. ... The first is the systolic pressure.
    </string>
    <string name="what_is_stress">What is Stress?</string>
    <string name="answer_to_stress">Stress is the body reaction to any change that requires an adjustment or response. The body reacts to these changes with physical, mental, and emotional responses. Stress is a normal part of life. ... Even positive life changes such as a promotion, a mortgage, or the birth of a child produce stress.
</string>
    <string name="card_view_string_1">A normal diastolic blood pressure is lower than 80. But even if your diastolic number is lower than 80, you can have elevated blood pressure if the systolic reading is 120-129.

80-89 is stage 1 hypertension.

90 or more is stage 2 hypertension.

120 or more is a hypertensive crisis. Call 911.</string>
    <string name="symptoms_of_high_blood_pressure">
        Severe headache,
Fatigue or confusion,
Vision problems,
Chest pain,
Difficulty breathing,
Irregular heartbeat,
Blood in the urine,
Pounding in your chest, neck, or ears</string>
    <string name="symptoms_of_low_blood_pressure">
        Dizziness or lightheadedness,
Fainting (syncope),
Blurred vision,,
Nausea,
Fatigue,
Lack of concentration
    </string>
    <string name="injury_defination">noun. Injury is defined as harm to a person or thing. An example of an injury is breaking your leg in a soccer game. An example of an injury is hurting someone reputation.</string>
    <string name="what_is_three_type_of_injuries">Three types of injuries: acute, overuse and chronic
Common examples include wrist fractures, ankle sprains, shoulder strains dislocations, and muscle strains.</string>
    <string name="what_are_seven_sport_injuries">Ankle sprain,
Groin pull,
Hamstring strain,
Shin splints,
Knee injury: ACL tear,
Knee injury: Patellofemoral syndrome — injury resulting from the repetitive movement of your kneecap against your thigh bone.
Tennis elbow (epicondylitis)</string>
    <string name="symptoms_of_moderate_head_injury">
        Symptoms of a moderate head injury include:

passing out for a short time
confusion or distraction
vomiting
a lasting headache
temporary changes in behavior
memory problems
loss of balance
    </string>
    <string name="symptoms_of_severe_head_injury">Symptoms of a severe head injury include:

significant bleeding
passing out and not waking up
having a seizure
problems with vision, taste, or smell
difficulty staying alert or awake
clear fluid or blood coming out of the ears or nose
bruises behind the ears
weakness or numbness
difficulty speaking</string>
    <string name="when_to_see_a_doctor">Moderate and severe head injuries require immediate treatment. If the symptoms of a mild head injury last for more than 2 weeks, a person should also seek medical advice.

The symptoms of a concussion do not always appear immediately. Sometimes, a person may develop initial symptoms days or weeks after the injury.

People should always take head injuries seriously. If someone is concerned about their symptoms, even after a mild injury, they should speak to a doctor.</string>
</resources>
